好的，让我们一起解决这些问题。
Okay, let's get through these together.
我们在一起，你们都在一起。
We're in this together y'all.
所以，一旦我把你带到黑暗的一面，我们都必须知道如何
So, once I bring you all over to the dark side, we all have to know how
一起做这件事，这样我们才能说服别人这是好的。
to do this together so we can convince others that it's good.
所以有这个。
So there's this.
我想从没有 foldMap 的不可变 Js 中调出列表。
I wanted to call out lists from immutable Js it does not have foldMap.
所以我们使用的是不可变的扩展，这只是我使用了一个可变的和
So we're using immutable extensions, which is just I took a mutable and
添加 foldMap 到它。
added foldMap to it.
但是有 50 个不同的库以完全相同的方式实现它。
But there's like 50 different libraries that implement it exactly the same way.
所以我们只是用这个来演示它，但是你看到了，
So we're just using this one just to demonstrate it, but you saw,
它只是减少，您只需传入类型。
it's just reduce and you just pass in the type.
好的，所以它说重新实现一些使用折叠映射和求和幺半群。
Okay, so it says to re implement some using fold map and the sum monoid.
好的，让我们在这里使用 foldMap 。
Okay, let's use foldMap here.
所以我们有 x 的列表，我们将点击而不是调用这个累加器
So we have list of x's and we're going to hit instead of calling this accumulator
和 x 0，我们将从 Sum(0) 开始，或者只是 Sum.empty 怎么样？
and the x 0, we'll start with the Sum(0), or how about just Sum.empty?
并传入 Sum 和 foldMap。
And Pass in Sum and foldMap.
所以我们要拿这个 xs 列表，把它们变成和，从空开始。
So we're gonna take this list of xs, turn them into sums, starting with empty.
现在，因为 xs，实际上那里有东西，如果我不这样做，它就不会破裂。
Now, since xs, there's actually stuff there, it's not gonna break if I don't.
不，我想它会坏的，好吧，没关系。
No, I guess it is gonna break, all right, that's fine.
[笑] 我已经更新了库，所以它的工作方式更像是 reduce。
[LAUGH] I've updated the library so it works more like reduce.
如果它不存在，它不会破坏，但它应该在那里，所以处理它。
It doesn't break if it's not there, but It should be there, so deal with it.
但是 foldMap 可以在半群上工作，这只是一个不安全的操作。
But foldMap can work on semigroups, it's just an unsafe operation.
所以有那个，有任何问题吗？
So there's that one, any questions on that?
有人挣扎过吗？
Did anybody have any struggles?
也许这有点太模棱两可了。
And maybe this was a little too ambiguous.
&gt;&gt; [笑] 好的，很好的问题。
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] All right, great question.
这究竟是如何工作的？
How does this work, exactly?
那么发生的事情是，我们有这个 123，对吗？
So what's happening is, we have this 123, right?
foldMap 实际上是怎么回事。
What's going on with foldMap actually is.
让我们继续以不同的方式编写 foldMap 。
Let's let's go ahead and write foldMap in a different way.
FoldMap 需要一个类型，对吧？
FoldMap takes a type, right?
让我们称之为 t 这样我们就不会像您的关键字 air 那样奇怪
Let's call that t so we don't have some weird like your keyword air and
一堆x。
a bunch of x's.
我们会说 xs reduce 会带你累加器和每个 x，
We'll say xs reduce will take you accumulator and each x,
我们要说的是这实际上需要三个参数。
and we're gonna put was this it takes actually three arguments.
第一个，我们要推过去，对吧？
This first one, we're gonna push over here, right?
所以它不是空的，好吧，还有x。
So it's t then of empty, all right, and the x's.
所以我们可以从空开始
So we can start with empty here
因为我们的初始累加器只会执行 aq concat x。
as our initial accumulator will just do aq concat x.
所以这就是 foldMap 在幕后实现的方式，它只是一个减少。
So this is how foldMap is implemented under the hood, it's just a reduce.
所以这里发生的事情是，如果我们继续调用 foldMap，
So what's happening here is if we go ahead and stead and call foldMap,
一些空的和我们希望仍然通过的 xs。
some some of the empty and our xs that should hopefully still pass.
我们得到一个楠，楠。
We get a Nan, Nan.
怎么看？
How's that looking?
我们得到了一些这种类型，这是我没有把它放在 t 中。
We got this type some, which is t I didn't put it in the t.
这就是这个权利的症结所在，现在它已经过去了
That's the that's kind of the crux of this right is that and now it's passing
是当我们说 foldMap 时，我们是说我们要将这个列表向下折叠 123。
is that when we say foldMap, we're saying we want to fold this list down 123.
但首先我们要把它映射到子类型，就是这个映射，比例，
But first we want to map it into the subtype, that's this map, proportion,
这里的一部分。
a portion here.
所以我们也可以不把 t 放在这里，
So we could alternatively instead of putting the t here,
我们实际上可以说，第一张地图，把它放在类型里，
we could actually say, first map, put it in the type,
然后通过对所有内容调用 concat 来减少它，我们仍然通过。
then reduce it down just by calling concat on everything, and we still pass.
所以这就是它在引擎盖下的工作方式。
So this is kind of how it works under the hood.
如果我们回到刚刚得到 xs 列表的另一种语法，
If we go back to the other syntax where we've just got a list of xs and
我们将把它折叠成一个总和。
we're going to foldMap that into a sum.
我们可以通过说我们已经得到每个 x 来扩展它，我们会
We can expand this by saying we've got each x and we're gonna
把它放在 sum 类型中，然后它就知道如何将它们组合起来。
put that in the sum type and then it just knows how to combine them all.
所以还有另一个功能它没有提到它只是完整的。
So there is another function that it didn't mention which is just full.
因此，假设我有，并且它是空的。
So let's say I have and it ticks an empty.
假设我有一个列表，我们对其进行映射，然后将其放入总和中
Let's say I have a list and we map over it and we put that into a sum and
我们只是折叠那个列表。
we just fold down that list.
FoldMap 只是先映射它然后折叠它，
FoldMap is just first map it then fold it,
fold 是这部分，我们只是连接所有内容。
fold being this this part where we just concat everything.
所以，这就是名称折叠地图的来源。
So, that's where the name fold map comes from.
折叠只是将所有内容连接到我的列表中
Fold is just concat everything into my list
因为我列表中的所有内容都有一个 concat 方法。
because everything in my list has a concat method.
我们只会得到一件事，我们将结构折叠成一个值。
And we would just end up with one thing, we fold the structure down into one value.
而且fold和map都不是专门列出来的。
And fold and map are not specialized to list.
我们可以在树上这样做，我们可以在事件流上这样做，
We can do this on trees, we can do this on events stream,
我们可以在许多不同的数据结构上做到这一点，这些数据结构甚至可以保存集合
we can do this on many different data structures that hold collections even
要么你可以把它折叠出来，对吧？
either you would be able to fold map it out of the either, right?
所以foldMap非常有用，fold非常有用。
So foldMap is very useful, fold is very useful.
它来自一个名为 foldable 的界面和
Its from an interface called foldable and
如果我们有幺半群和半群可供我们使用，
if we have monoids and semi groups at our disposal,
它是函数式编程中最有用的方法之一。
its one of the most useful methods in functional programming.
好的，让我们继续。
Okay, let's move on.
我希望回答了你的问题，多做一点，好吧。
I hope that answered your question, did it a little bit more, okay.
&gt;&gt; 这可能是列表的实现问题，
&gt;&gt; This may be an implementation issue with lists,
但是我在尝试将 xs 传递给 list.of 时挂断了电话。
but I got hung up trying to pass xs to list.of.
&gt;&gt; 是的，太好了。
&gt;&gt; Yes, so that's great.
所以 Mutable JS 确实创建了指针函数。
So Mutable JS does create pointers functions.
我可以说一个包含两个的列表，这会将我放入一个列表中。
And I could say a list of two, and that would put me in a list.
但是如果我说的是两个数组的列表，
But if I said list of an array of two,
那将列出一个包含两个列表的列表。
that would put a list of a list of two.
我们把它搬进去。
We're lifting that in.
如果我只调用两个列表，就像，嘿，你不是一个数组，所以，
And if I just call a list of two, it's like, hey, you're not an array so,
这适用于这种情况，这适用于这种情况。
this would work for that case, this would work for this case.
所以这个强迫它的善良
So this one's coercing it's kind
一堆可能是正确的方法。
of a bunch of is kind of probably the the proper way.
它就在下面，我有一个清单，正在传递给它。
It's just down here, I have a list, passing into it.
非常酷。
So cool.
任何小于零或任何小于零。
Anything less than zero or any less than zero.
所以这说，好吧，我们正在尝试对 foldMap 进行编程，然后
So this says, okay, we're trying to program the foldMap and
我们试图看到，它的一些效用是这样的。
we're trying to see, some of its utility here like this.
这些示例有点像玩具示例，了解如何调用的人体工程学
These examples are kinda toy examples, getting the ergonomics around how to call
foldMap 并将东西放入类型并取出。
foldMap and put things into types and take them out.
但是当你开始做一些建筑方面的事情时
But when you start to do some of the architectural stuff, and
我们将在此之后看到一些示例并构建一个小库，这里会发生什么
we'll see some examples following this and build a little library, what happens here
那是类型级联，对吗？
is that the types cascade, right?
所以你实际上是在结合效果和值并做出分支决策和
So you're actually combining effects and values and making branching decisions and
使用完整的 foldMap 进行所有这些非常密集的计算，并且
doing all this really intense computation with a full foldMap and
它直观地捕捉它。
it's capturing it intuitively.
所以这些都是非常小的、简单的例子，但你可以想象这就像我
So these are really small, easy examples, but you can imagine this is like I've
得到一个异步、错误、填充的列表，
got a list of Async, error, filled,
就像任何决策价值观一样，然后我们就走上了正确的道路。
like whatever decision making values and then we kinda go down the right path.
所以让我们继续在这里写 foldMap 。
So let's go ahead and write foldMap here.
就像以前一样，我们只是要做 foldMap any，
And just like before, we're just gonna do foldMap any,
和any.empty，这行得通吗？
and any.empty, does that work?
它确实有效。
It does work.
那里发生什么了？
What happened there?
你得到负二。
You get negative two.
那是什么？
What is that?
这小于零，对不起我的错。
This is less than zero, sorry my bad.
它说重新实现了使用任何单声道 ID。
It says re-implemented that using the any mono-id.
好吧，没关系。
Okay, that's fine.
我们很好。
We're fine.
所以一个折叠 Map 如果它小于零，我们将返回 true，好吧。
So a fold Map and if this is less than zero, we're gonna return true, all right.
任何真的。
Any true.
我们走了。
There we go.
否则任何错误，我们将从任何空开始。
Otherwise any false and we'll start with any empty.
怎么样？
How does that go?
好的，现在它过去了，你看看它是如何工作的。
All right now it's passing you see how that works.
我很困惑，因为我只是不假思索地遵循我的模板。
I got confused because I was just following my template without thinking.
但这个想法是 any 不带零它需要一个数字。
But the idea is that any doesn't take a zero It takes a number.
它需要一个布尔值，所以我们可以做我们的布尔值，然后返回任何。
It takes a Boolean so we can do our Boolean, then return the any.
然后我将把它们全部结合起来。
And then I'll just combine all of them.
&gt;&gt; 只是为了确保我没有在自己的代码中进行幼稚的技术转换。
&gt;&gt; Just to make sure that I'm not making a naive technical switch in my own code.
我放入了一个 lambda 函数，然后传入任何
I put a lambda function in and then passed in any
x 小于零，这也通过。
with x less than zero and that also comes through.
这只是从架构上检查。
That checks but architecturally.
&gt;&gt; 任何东西。
&gt;&gt; Anything.
&gt;&gt; 我做了一个里面的比较。
&gt;&gt; I did the comparison inside of one any.
&gt;&gt; 那样？
&gt;&gt; Like that?
&gt;&gt; 到达那里，但您只是使用了 x 而不是累加器。
&gt;&gt; Getting there but you just used the x not the accumulator.
&gt;&gt; 刚刚使用。
&gt;&gt; Just using.
&gt;&gt; 是的，如果你取出累加器，把 x 小于 0。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, if you take out the accumulator, put x less than 0.
然后把问号后面的东西拿出来，
And then take out anything after the question mark,
因为那是隐含在该操作中的。
because that's implicit in that operation.
那是，那正在过去，但我改变了什么吗？
Is that, that is passing, but am I changing anything?
我想你必须拿出一个ACC谢谢你。
I think you've got to take out an ACC thank you.
那就对了。
That's right.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
没错， foldMap 不接受。
That's right, foldMap doesn't take in.
抱歉，我错了，foldMap 不带累加器，对吗？
Sorry, I had this wrong, foldMap doesn't take an accumulator, right?
蓄能器现在不见了。
The accumulator is now gone.
所以它只会在后台保存那个累加器。
So it's just going to hold that accumulator in the background.
你在这里关心的只是保留一个。
All you're concerned about here is just keeping one.
所以这实际上是编写相同内容的更简单的方法，谢谢。
So this is actually a much simpler way to write the same thing, thank you.
&gt;&gt; 好的，谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Okay, thank you.
&gt;&gt; 所以我们正在做的是说。
&gt;&gt; So what we're doing is saying.
我需要获取一个数字列表并将它们转换为一个实体列表，然后
I need to take a list of numbers and turn them into a list of entities and
把它们变成一个列表，我得到了一个函数和
to turn them into a list I'm given a function and
现在我有一个实体列表，任何小于零的东西，很酷。
now I have a list of entities, anything less than zero, cool.
&gt;&gt; 我的做法也有点不同，
&gt;&gt; I did it a little bit differently too,
我先打电话给 map 把数字变成玻利维亚酷，然后
I called map first to turn the numbers into Bolivians Cool, and then
称为折叠地图将布尔值放入 &gt;&gt; 是的，听起来不错。
called fold map to put the Booleans in &gt;&gt; Yeah, sounds great.
所以像这样你映射每个 x，并说 x 小于零。
So something like this where you map each x, and say x less than zero.
所以另一个真假，在这里给你任何。
So another trues and falses, and give you any here.
是的，这很好。
Yeah, that's nice.
这样做的好方法。
It's good way to do that.
你也可以在这里做任何事情，然后把它折叠起来。
You could also do any here and then just fold it down.
所以 foldMap 只是结合了文件夹和
And so foldMap just combines the folder and
当地图几乎无关紧要时，为了提高效率，将地图整合为一件事。
the map into one thing for efficiency when it almost never matters.
[笑]对不起，我永远不会停止说[笑]。
[LAUGH] Sorry I'm never gonna stop saying that [LAUGH].
好的，让我们这样做。
Okay, so let's do this.
我们有最大的。
We have the max.
所以这里还有两个我们将通过这些，max 是非常可爱的幺半群。
So there's two more left here we'll get through these, max is pretty sweet monoid.
我们实际上可以看看这个，但我们从负无穷开始。
We can actually look at this one yet, but we start with negative infinity.
我最喜欢的值，我们说，好吧，好吧，
My favorite value and we say, all right, well,
是否大于 x 的累加器。
the accumulator greater than x or not.
所以它说用最大幺半群重写它。
So it says rewrite it with a max monoid.
它说它说实际上使用上面的这些模板制作一个最大幺半群。
And it says it says to actually make a max monoid using these templates above.
我只是要复制这个，把它放到这个部分。
I'm just going to copy this, bring it down here into this part.
有人收到这个吗？
Did anybody get this one?
这个有点棘手。
This one's a little bit tricky.
并没有真正觉得他们卡在捷径上。
Didn't really feel like they got stuck on the shortcut.
这实际上只是将这个运算符替换为 max 运算符的问题。
It’s really just a matter of swapping out this operator with the max operator.
我们不需要，我想我们可以做最大 x 负无穷大，对吧？
We don’t need the, I guess we can do the max x negative infinity, right?
所以这是与第二个参数对应的空值。
So that’s the empty value over here corresponding with the second argument.
这对应于我们所说的第一个参数是否更大
This is corresponding to the first argument where we're saying is it greater
比 x 或者实际上看起来这就是我们需要做的。
than x or actually looks like this is what we need to do.
我们只能抢了。
We can just grab in.
我们会说，A，x 是否大于 ox？
We'd say, A, is x greater than o x?
好吧，那我们就保留x。
Well, then we'll keep x.
否则我们将保留 o x。
Otherwise we'll keep o x.
意思是我们试图比较的其他 Mac。
Meaning the other other Mac's that we're trying to compare to.
然后我们将继续将其重写为
And then we'll go ahead and rewrite this as
一个 foldMmap 与 Max 和
a foldMmap with Max and
马克斯，空传。
Max, empty passing.
是的，我们要过去了。
Yeah, we're passing.
那么，关于这个问题？
So, questions on this one?
这个有点你知道，你正在制作一个幺半群
This one's a little bit you know, you're making a monoid
有点遵循上面的模式，但这有点不同，对吧？
kind of following the pattern above but this was a little different, right?
我最初的想法是，让我们换掉操作员，但这不是它的工作原理。
I was initially like, let's swap out the operator but that's not how it works.
您在这里做出选择，您必须选择其中之一。
You're making a choice here you have to choose one or the other.
所以大于或小于只是给我一个布尔值，等等
So the greater than or less than just give me a Boolean, and so
我会有问题。
I would have had a problem.
最后，我们将在这里为 tuple 或 tuple 编写 concat，但是，你说出来。
Finally, we're gonna write concat here for tuple or tuple however, you say it.
而这个有点酷。
And this one's kinda cool.
就像我们说的函子和其他一样，实际上，
Just like we said functors and other, actually,
如果我们在上面写地图，这是一个函子，点击选择一个来映射。
this is a functor if we write map on it, which tap to pick one to map over.
如果您想同时映射两者，则它是双函子。
It's bi-functor if you want to map over both.
但关键是，我们要把元组作为一个类型变成
But the point is, we want to make tuple as a type into
一个幺半群或半群通过给它一个 concat 方法。
a monoid or semi-group by giving it a concat method.
所以如果我有另一个元组。
So if I have another tuple.
我可以说一个 concat 好 concat
I could say one concat well concat
我的 0.1 对吗？
my one with 0.1 right?
我们会把它放在桌子上。
We'll keep it in the table.
它总是关闭的，对吧？
It's always closed, right?
然后我们让我看看它与其他的连接起来。
And then we have my to look at it concat it with the other ones.
两个还好，我没事。
Two and fine, I'm okay.
代码笔你不用警告我，明白了。
Code pen you don't have to warn me, got it.
[笑] 我觉得自己像个脾气暴躁的少年，而 Code pen 是我的父母。
[LAUGH] I feel ike a surly teenager and Code pen is my parent.
所以这就是它的工作原理，我们是说，我持有两个值。
So this is how that works, we're saying, I'm holding two values.
如果我可以连接我持有的所有东西，那么我，我自己就可以连接。
And if I can concat everything I'm holding, then I, myself can be concated.
这只是在等待，所以我有一个完全由
And that just awaits holds, so I have a type that's entirely built of
可合并的东西，我可以合并我持有的所有东西，我们就在那里。
concatable things, I can just concat all the stuff I'm holding and there we are.
所以现在我可以将任何东西放入元组或元组中。
So now I can put anything into a tuple or a tuple.
我还没有确定我要说的方式。
I haven't fixed which way I'm gonna say it yet.
所以两者 [笑] 这很讽刺，因为它包含两件事。
So both [LAUGH] which is ironic because it holds two things.